Oh, they're not dead. Looks like they're just paralyzed.
Must have been those things. Can you heal them?
I'll see.
Well, I hope you had a decent nap.
What happened? Did we get wiped out?
Wait, where's my necklace?
Damn it! My coins are gone too!
I can't find any of the jewels either.
Some of our belongings have gone missing.
Did you see what happened?
There's no doubt. Treasure insects.
Shh! Sorry, couldn't tell you.
When we got here, you guys were just laying by the wall all lined up.
So I'm willing to bet that someone came here before we did.
This is hair.
It's used to repel ghosts.
Apparently, there was someone else who found us.
Hmm.
Elf.
A tall man.
Half foot.
A dwarf, too.
They ate a meal in this exact spot.
They what?
Who would have the nerve to do that?
Come on!
Not so fast.
This ain't a charity.
Here.
Thanks, kid.
Why didn't you just tell him the truth?
Why should I?
More corpses means more money, after all.
I hope I can wash my hair soon.
Save the trouble and shave it off.
You really don't have to be so mean to me, you know.
Bet you really want to wash your beard, right, Senshi?
You don't even comb that thing, do you?
We need to clean it now.
Hair is actually pretty important for magic.
Taking care of it is kind of like doing warm-up exercises.
If your beard's dirty, then my support magic might not work on you.
That's fine by me.
Oh, I just remembered I have some good soap with me.
Let's wash your beard with that and braid it after.
Hmm?
Uh, where is it?
Ah!
Back then, it must have...
It's all gone!
It got so much money!
Let's go.
The fourth floor.
Underground water rushes out of holes in the bedrock,
forming a large lake.
The water is imbued with magic and glows faintly.
At the bottom of the lake, you can see the castle town,
rippling like a mirage.
Hey, Senshi, what exactly do you do when you're exploring this floor?
I usually just fish or lay traps all around this area.
That's about it.
How do you folks get past this point?
Isn't it obvious?
Magic, of course.
Check it out.
First, I do this.
And then we just walk across the water.
No!
No, no, no, no, no!
You don't have to throw such a fit.
I don't think you can make me!
This isn't gonna work.
Tie him up and pull him along.
Marcel?
Go ahead and cast your spell while I hold him down!
Huh?
Hurry!
Senshi, this is the only way to do it, wearing armor!
The boat is too risky!
Cut!
People are so quick to give in to the simple path.
It only takes a second to rust, but to sharpen it takes a long time!
You see, that didn't kill you, did it?
Why, you little...
I honestly don't get it.
Why are you so opposed to magic?
You wanna know what I don't get?
How you lot can throw around spells all willy-nilly.
It's careless.
Hey, come on.
What's done is done, isn't it?
Who knows?
You might even end up...
...liking it!
Huh?
Wait, what?
Why is the spell so ineffective?
Is it because maybe his hair works as an insulator?
Seems likely with all this monster blood and oil kicked in...
Seriously?
Wash that gross thing already!
It'll take much more than water.
There's no need.
Don't worry about me.
I'll cross the lake my own way.
You gonna make a boat?
He'll just sink like a stone.
Hold on.
I bet whatever idea he came up with is awesome.
What's with the sudden, unwavering faith?
He must be losing it.
Just watch.
The shell of a mimic?
Shh!
Oh.
Kelby!
Careful!
It's getting closer!
Calm down.
She's harmless.
Anne here often comes to visit me when I'm trying to catch fish.
You named it?
I've always been curious about whether or not I could cross the lake with her.
Maybe I can use a mimic shell as bait to help lead her over to the other side.
Really?
That would be...
...absolutely incredible!
I'm against this.
If we used its organs as a life preserver, it'd be more useful.
That's awful!
I can't believe you just said that.
All monsters are dangerous.
Friendly ones are no exception.
Kelpies try to lower your guard to coax you into the water.
You never know a monster's true intentions.
Look, I've known Anne for just as long as I've known the golems.
So don't try and tell me I don't know her.
Why are people so soft when it comes to mammals, yet they're totally against growing man-eating plants?
Uh, do you really need me to explain it?
All right, Anne.
Let's go.
Sanshi!
Here, catch!
Anne.
Stop it, Anne.
You can't die!
So she was just waiting for me to get on her back?
Why?
She could have attacked whenever.
Yeah.
I can't even begin to understand how monsters think.
I don't get it.
I don't get it one bit.
Hey.
Aren't you freezing?
I could start a fire.
Wait.
You loved her so much, but you're going to eat her?
I can't believe it.
Why do this?
Need a hand?
No.
I'm doing this alone.
Hmm.
Hey.
If it's no trouble, could I have a little bit of the fat?
Weren't you opposed to me doing this?
I was.
I was, but...
Seriously.
What did we even come here for?
Chill, Chuck.
Huh?
There's something floating over there, and I'm worried it's people.
Let's go.
Do we have to?
What are these little white things?
Barley.
Must be leaking from a bag.
Well, I found the owners.
Yeah.
Let's get them back to land.
Huh?
What's wrong?
He looks familiar.
Have we seen this guy before?
Nope.
Oh, I remember this kobold.
We saw him knocked out on the third floor, too.
How'd these guys get ahead of us?
Jeez.
They fought fishmen, huh?
That's unlucky.
Uh-huh.
Chill, Chuck?
Hey!
Chill, Chuck!
Stop!
I didn't get to finish singing it again.
I even learned it all, too.
Oh.
I think that should do it.
I feel bad that their barley's scattered.
Should we help them?
I doubt they would still want it.
Then let's take it with us.
It'll make Marcelle happy.
No, I don't think it will.
Huh?
No way!
I didn't say anything yet.
We all agreed that demi-humans are off limits, remember?
Okay, but think about it.
What are demi-humans?
What'd you just say?
There are different types of mermaids.
The mammal type and the fish type.
This is the fish type.
It has gills and lays eggs, so there's no belly button or nipples.
Classification-wise, they're farther from humans than cows or pigs.
Dylan, no!
Tell me what's wrong with it!
Why is a cow okay, but a fish man somehow isn't?
It just doesn't feel right to me, okay?
Feel right?
Feelings, huh?
They're still going at it.
I'm hungry, so let's start making something to eat.
Soak the barley and put it over a flame.
Pull apart some mimic meat and add a few water plants.
Hold on a second.
Wasn't that growing out of the fish man's head?
I mean, yes, but this is also a completely ordinary plant.
Fish men use these to mimic the mermaids.
Without it, they would probably look a lot more like fish.
Fish, you're not going to let me eat it, are you?
Here we go again.
All right, whatever.
Do what you want.
Why do I get the feeling that I just made a huge mistake?
All right, it's ready.
Come on, you two.
Time for lunch.
Is it that time already?
Hey, where did you get this barley from?
It was near some dead adventurers, so he nabbed it.
What were you thinking?
Yeah, we probably shouldn't have done that.
Well, it's already cooked.
It doesn't matter.
Thanks a lot for making lunch.
Something's popping in my mouth.
I wonder what that is.
Fish eggs, maybe?
They might have been stuck in the water plants.
Mmm, it's tasty.
Yeah, it is, isn't it?
Glad I put them in.
Can we talk?
Hey, those were the fish men's eggs, weren't they?
I heard that they lay eggs and hide them in water plants.
Specifically the ones that are growing straight out of their heads.
Everything good?
Depends.
Does that taste okay?
Hmm.
Sure does!
Senshi?
This is for you.
Hmm?
I made some soap from the kelpie fat you gave me.
Not only is it useful as a hair oil,
but it's good for using on clothes and dishes, too.
Do you mind if we use it right now?
Well, it may not be fully effective just yet.
That's fine with me.
I want to make use of your hard work.
You really do?
No?
I see.
If this experience has taught me anything,
it's that walking on water feels nicer than I ever imagined it'd be.
So thanks, Marcel.
Mm-hmm.
I think the soap's starting to sting my eyes a little.
Leave it to me!
I'm gonna wipe them all out!
No! Stop!
Watch out!
I said stop, didn't I?
Using an explosion in the water kills too many of them!
What?
These are bladefish, which can be boiled, grilled, steamed, dried, smoked, or eaten raw.
No matter how you do it, they taste delicious.
But other monsters here eat them too.
If their numbers dwindle, it's gonna affect the dungeon's ecosystem for sure.
So if you kill them, do it one at a time.
Huh? That's not even possible!
Come to think of it, there does seem to be fewer mid-sized monsters.
There, see?
Okay, but they're trying to kill us, aren't they?
So I can't really go easy on them.
Plus, there's a lot more bladefish than usual anyway.
I don't think there's anything to worry about.
Don't you care if we starve?
I'd rather not die to preserve a monster's ecosystem!
Typical.
Always want to take these away.
You did?
You and I couldn't get one at a time yet.
But why are you still going to stop?
You need to be more considerate of the ecosystem.
Huh?
Whoa!
What's going on?
Senshi!
That was weird.
They went right past us.
Are you hurt?
Senshi?
There's something coming this way.
Huh?
Whatever this thing is!
It's huge!
A squid?
No.
Octopus?
Wait, that's a kraken!
It's already a large monster to begin with.
But this one is much bigger than normal.
So awesome!
What now?
If we're not careful, we're done for!
Let's go distract it.
Do your thing, Marcel.
More magic, huh?
It's a big target, so it'll be fine.
Here he comes!
Don't stop!
Gotcha!
Hey, I did it!
No way!
That barely scratched it!
So weapons can only damage a thin layer of its skin.
Hmm.
Huh?
This is bad!
What spell do I use?
Marcel!
Do you mind using that magic again?
What?
I can't just keep firing explosions at it!
Not that.
This one.
It's your first time seeing a kraken, right, Senshi?
Do you know anything about it?
Nope.
What?
I don't know a lick about krakens, but I have handled squid and octavi.
Marcel!
It's heading your way!
Here it goes!
Water walking!
When killing squid and octopi, you stab right between the eyes!
Unbelievable!
Wait!
Where's Lyos?
Huh?
Hey!
I'm...
Over here!
I think this might be why there are fewer mid-sized monsters on this floor.
You two!
Huh?
Come here!
I want to make sure that you both understand how to handle seafood.
For squid and octopi, you'll get a clean kill if you stab here.
Are squid and octopi any good?
No way!
You've never eaten them before?
You really can't go wrong with either!
Boil them, grill them, steam them, or dry them, smoke them, or eat them raw!
No matter how you prepare them, they're both super tasty!
Oh, yeah!
And I know a good spot!
I'll tell you later!
Can't we eat it now?
What have I done?
Whoa!
This is so good!
I don't understand how to handle seafood.
For squid and octopi, you'll get a clean kill if you stab here.
Are squid and octopi any good?
No way!
You've never eaten them before?
You really can't go wrong with either!
Can't we eat it now?
What have I done?
Whoa!
This is so weird!
How do we eat this?
Try it with a little pinch of salt first.
It stinks!
Really?
Why?
Why so better?
The inside of my mouth is tingling.
You actually put this in everything you eat, Marsu?
Now wait just a sec!
I never said I did that!
Hmm?
Huh?
Wow!
How amazing!
I can't believe big monsters have big parasites!
Why else I'm gonna hurl!
Get rid of that thing!
What are you making such a fuss about?
All living things have parasites.
And a lot of them end up getting mixed into the things we eat, too.
I didn't ask for any trivia!
So if we cook this, does that mean we can eat it?
Please, though!
Well, I don't see why we couldn't.
I don't wanna!
Why don't we try putting some sauce on this and grilling it?
Ugh!
I'm irritated because it's actually starting to smell good!
It's ready!
So good!
It's tender!
There is a little bit of sliminess to it.
But if you look past that, it's so flavorful and meaty!
Oh, wow!
It is good!
Yeah, not bad!
You would expect it to taste like fish, but it's pretty unique.
Do you think it's better than squid or octopi?
There's no way!
I mean, probably...
No matter how you prepare this, I bet it's still delicious.
I even liked how it tastes while raw!
Hold on!
You ate it raw?!
Well, just a bit.
But it was already dead.
I bet it's so flavorful and meaty!
Oh, wow!
It is good!
Yeah, not bad!
You would expect it to taste like fish, but it's pretty unique.
Do you think it's better than squid or octopi?
There's no way!
I mean, probably...
No matter how you prepare this, I bet it's still delicious.
I even liked how it tastes while raw!
Hold on!
You ate it raw?!
Well, just a bit.
But it was already dead, so it's fine.
Check it out!
The fish are eating the kraken!
Now the population of mid-sized monsters should gradually recover.
My stomach's feeling...
Are you okay?
What happened?
I see...
Thought so.
Lyos?
Seems you managed to catch a parasite from eating the giant parasite.
They're typically inside normal fish as well.
I saw it when I was cutting it up.
Oh, no.
They don't feed on humans.
But once inside, they will rip holes in your stomach.
Well, I guess we'll have to wait until the bug dies.
I might be the one to die first.
Hit him with healing magic every so often.
All right.
This is very interesting.
The fishmen prey on the bladefish, and the kraken eat the fishmen.
We defeat the kraken, and then the tiny fish eat the meat from its carcass.
Lyos ate the kraken's parasite, and now the parasite from that parasite is forming a hole in his stomach.
I might have been a bit too arrogant in thinking that I could protect the ecosystem here.
But as it turns out, we were already included in the dungeon cycle from the very beginning.
Lyos wanted to say something, but due to the intense pain and urge to vomit, he couldn't quite form a sentence.
The distinct feeling of having a knife slashing at his insides continued through the night.
Afterward, he vowed never to consume a raw parasite ever again.
To be continued...